Guide to the Plácido Vega Papers, 1855-1864
Department of Special Collections
- Continuation of Folder 120 (Box 10, Folder 121)
  - Palmar, San Juan Bautista: letters to Plácido Vega from I. Pompa, Jesús Vega, Felipe Vega, others.
  - Ocoroni: letters to Plácido Vega from J.M.Rodríguez, others.
  - Mocorito: letters to Plácido Vega from I. Orrantia, B. Insunza, C. Riberos, certificate pertaining to Kelly-Myrtle transaction.
  - Acaponeta: letters to Plácido Vega from I. López de Alemán, other.
  - Durango: letters to Plácido Vega from J.M.Patoni, J. Aguiluz, B. Silva, others.
  - Rosario: letters to Plácido Vega from D. Rubí, Juan Paredes, José Hermosillo, M. Figueroa, others.
  - Culiacán: letters to Plácido Vega from Antonio Vega, José M. de la Vega, C. Vega, Francisco de la Vega, Joaquín Vega, B. Almada, Antonio Ramos, Antonio Paredes, I. Pesquiera, M. Martínez, J. Tirado, R. Prieto, A. Ángulo, M. Serrano, G. Verdugo, F. M. Bulnes, Clemente E. de los Monteros, L. Tirado, M. Romero, A. Blancarte, I. Isabal, J. Arzapalo, G. MacKintosh, M. Zerón (including copy of articles prepared for submission to Constitutional Congress in December, 1861.
- Continuation of Folder 121. (Box 10, Folder 122)
  Correspondence: letters to Plácido Vega organized by district, etc., (1861-1863).
  - Baja California: letters to Plácido Vega from J. Riveroli, M.Rojo.
  - Hermosillo: letters to Plácido Vega from I. Pesquiera, J.M.Iribarren.
  - Quilá: letters to Plácido Vega from Carlos Ochoa, others.
  - Conetaca: letters to Plácido Vega from Cayetano F. y Tejada.
  - Concordia: letters to Plácido Vega from Juan Paredes, I. Peraza, J. Arellano, Joaquín Valdez, others.
  - Mochicuhui: letters to Plácido Vega from J.W.Correl, Pedro Valenzuela.
  - Chihuahua: letters to Plácido Vega from Crispín Palomares, J. Arzapalo, V. Ortiz, M. Ortiz, R. Félix y Buelna, M. Urrea, G. Hill, B. Insunza, others. List of prisoners under command of Captain R. Sandavaso. Record of proceedings concerning Antonio Valázquez. Financial statement submitted by M. Rodríguez; notice of orders received by C. Palomares.
- (1861-1862) (Box 10, Folder 123)
  - Continuation of Folder 122 (1861-1862)
    Correspondence: letters to Plácido Vega organized by district, etc.
    - Capirato: letters to Plácido Vega from J. Trinidad.
    - Badiraguato: letter to Plácido Vega from M. Galacas?
    - Méjico: letters to Placido Vega from I. Comonfort (need for additional troops in capital); from M. Blanco (national crisis); from Benito Juárez (French invasion of Veracruz); from B. Almada (need for additional troops, etc.). Proclamation issued by Martín Salida in Chihuahua: need for soldiers (August, 1862).Letters to Plácido Vega from J. González Ortega, I. Zaragoza, F. Zarco, others.
    - Elote: letters to Plácido Vega from J. Sánchez, others.
    - Lagunita: letters to Plácido Vega from Máxime Peiros.
    - Guadalajara: letters to Plácido Vega from M. Doblado (financial crisis, etc); from P. Ogazón, I. Ortiz, others.
    - Colima: letters to Plácido Vega from I. Barreto, R. de la Vega, P. Ocampo, A. Barreto.
    - Tepusta: letter to Plácido Vega from F. Llebana [?]
    - Santiago: letter to Plácido Vega from E. Moore.
    - Fuerte: letters lacking.
- Documents, 1861-1863 (Box 11, Folder 124)
  Report (Mazatlán, 1862) giving account of uprising at Fuerte in 1861, including lists of soldiers, men taken prisoner, etc. Papers concerning Tepic and Ramón Corona. Report by R. Félix y Buelna of uprising at Fuerte. Papers pertaining to activities, capture, and sentencing of Antonio Esteves. Records of prefecture of Fuerte pertaining to uprising. Papers relating to proceedings against Francisco Orrantia and accomplices, 1862; judicial records, etc.
- Documents, 1861-1863 (Box 11, Folder 125)
  Records of information gathered by various authorities in Sonora, Sinaloa, and Chihuahua concerning uprising at Fuerte; papers pertaining to activities of accomplices; records of conversations held between Plácido Vega and those in charge of jail at Mazatlán in regard to jurisdiction over prisoners taken during uprising at Fuerte, etc.
- Documents, May, 1861 (Box 11, Folder 126)
  Statement by Calixto Peña giving notice of departure of expedition for Sonora with arms, munitions, etc. Records showing number of officers, doctors, active men, men ailing, by unit in Sinaloa; inventories of arms, clothing, etc. List of names of officers for brigade of army at Sinaloa. List of mules held by brigade; list of sergeants, enlisted men in battalion of Sinaloa; list of munitions. Lists of officers, enlisted men, etc. for squadron of Sinaloa. Financial records.
- Selected issues of army bulletins, 1860 (Box 11, Folder 127)
  Bulletins of First Division of Federal Army: issues of June 2, June 8, September 20, October 12, October 14, October 17, October 18, October 19, October 20, October 22, 1860. June issues printed at Ciudad Guzmán, and October issues at Guadalajara. Articles in issues preserved touch upon variety of subjects. In issue of June 2, column signed by P. Ogazon praises role of Plácido Vega and others at Alicia. Articles in successive issues lament death of patriots, praise division of Sinaloa, comment upon developments in various parts of Mexico, attempt to arouse patriotic enthusiasm of Mexicans. Issue of September 20 reprints excerpts purportedly taken from letters written by various individuals to Miramon.
  Issue of October 12 reprints articles of decree promulgated by Benito Juárez in July, 1859. Issues of succeeding days reprint articles or sections of decrees promulgated by Juárez in November, 1858, and in July and October, 1860. Issue of October 20 contains article referring to Tacubaya; issue of October 22 contains article praising General Zaragoza, and reprints article from circular printed in Veracruz concerning Comonfort.
- Documents, 1856-1863 (Box 11, Folder 128)
  Financial records of commanding officers in charge of sections of army at Sinaloa; financial statements, receipts, etc., of brigades, battalions, squadrons, divisions headed by Plácido Vega, I. Pesquiera, F.B. Ramírez, others. invoices held by Escuadrón de Lanceros; financial records of squadron and of Batallón Popular de Sinaloa; inventories.
- Sections of army bulletins, newspapers; documents; photographs. Printed matter from years 1861-1862. (Box 11, Folder 129)
  Issue of official paper of state La opinión de Sinaloa for April 6, 1861. Issue reprints articles or sections of decrees promulgated by Benito Juárez as interim Constitutional president in January, February, and March, 1861. Bulletins of the western division of the army at Sinaloa: issues of August 31, September 3, October 23, November 24, December 4, and December 9, 1861. Dates of other issues obliterated. Issue of October 23 contains article by Pesquiera telling of defeat of Esteves in October, 1861; second article (text damaged) tells of Blas Orrantia. Issue of December 4 tells of activities of Plácido Vega, Pesquiera, J. García Morales, E. Lamberg, and R. Félix y Buelna in Sonora in action to suppress Yaquis. Article includes lists of supplies purchased, charts of officers for units of Section of West, text of letters by chiefs of divisions or units of Section of West. Other issues reprint additional inventories, financial statements, and copies of letters by leading officers. Issue of August 31 contains article giving account of uprising at Fuerte. Folder also contains proclamation (diIapidated) issued by Plácido Vega in September, 1862, and envelope of photographs, many of which carry designations on reverse.